Kennedy, William; Papers mss132
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Investigative Journalism, 1957-1998; Undated; 17; 2.19 cu. ft.
  - State of New York Temporary Commission on Revision of the Penal Law and Criminal Code, Special Report on Capital Punishment, 1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 13)
  - Commission on Religion and Race Reports, 1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 14)
  - Post Daily Magazine Articles, "Dark Ghetto" Series, 1965 (Box 2 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 15)
  - Bill Kennedy "Slum" Articles, 1965 (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 1)
  - "Housing Series" Original Drafts, ca. 1965 (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 2)
  - "Poverty War Series" Original Drafts, ca. 1965 (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 3)
  - "Slum Series" Original Drafts, ca. 1965 (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 4)
  - Civil Rights Special Report, Button-Kennedy Memos, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Including Kennedy Articles on Poverty, Urban Issues, Housing, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 6)
  - "Slums" Clippings Information, 1965-1967; Undated (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 7)
  - Trinity Institution, Including Kennedy Articles and Notes, 1965-1998; Undated (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 8-9)
  - The New Republic, December 3 1966 (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 10)
  - Clergy Slum Tour, 1966 (Box 3 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 11)
  - Liberator Magazine, Vol. 6, No. 11, 1966 (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 1)
  - "Social Science Fiction in Harlem" Article, 1966 (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 2)
  - White House Conference Booklet "To Fulfill These Rights", 1966 (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 3-4)
  - Consumer Problems of the Poor Booklet, 1974 (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 5)
  - Housing in the City of Albany, 1977 (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 6)
  - Teachers & Writers Magazine, Vol. 12, No. 3, Arts in Harlem Issues, 1980-1981 (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 7)
  - Housing, 1980; 1982; 1986-1987; Undated (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 8)
  - New York Articles of Interest, 1994; Undated (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 9)
  - American Traveler's Guide to Negro History, Undated (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 10)
  - "Negro Interview Series" Original Drafts, Notes and Resume, Undated (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 11)
  - Blaming the Victim, Undated (Box 4 (17-Investigative Journalism), Folder 12)
- Biographical, 1969; 1983-2003; Undated; 18; 1.28 cu. ft.
  This series features biographical materials about William Kennedy. The majority of documents are news clippings about his work, book reviews and analysis, profile pieces, interview transcripts, articles featuring Kennedy's insights and comments on literature and the arts, and related correspondence. Of interest are newspaper clips and a program from Kennedy's first play Grand View which debuted at the Capital Repertory Theatre in Albany in 1996. There also is a VHS tape of William Kennedy's Albany which aired on PBS and a file discussing the celebration of the acquisition of this collection by the University at Albany. For articles written by Kennedy see Series 15: Essays and Articles or Series 17: Investigative Journalism.
  - Interviews for "Conversations with William Kennedy", 1969; 1983-1989; 1992-1997 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 1)
  - "An Interview with William Kennedy,"Fiction International, 1983-1986; Undated (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 2)
  - Kennedy Book Dust Jackets with Short Biographies, 1984; Undated (Oversized 10, Folder 1)
  - Visting Writers Program, Signed Poster and Reading Series, ca. 1984; ca. 1991; ca. 1995 (Oversized 10, Folder 2)
  - Kennedy Profile in Liberation, 1985 (Oversized 10, Folder 3)
  - "An Interview with William Kennedy," The Missouri Review, 1985 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 3)
  - Journalism Review, 1985 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 4)
  - "The Man Has Legs," Film Comment, 1985 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 5)
  - "William Kennedy: An Albany Aficionado," Meetings & Conversations, 1985 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 6)
  - "William Kennedy: An Interview," The Recorder, 1985; Undated (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 7)
  - "My High School English Teacher," Teachers and Writers, 1985-1986; 1994 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 8)
  - "An Interview with William Kennedy," University at Albany Publications, ca. 1987 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 9)
  - News Clippings, 1988 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 10)
  - "Public Radio Series: New Year, New Voices in American Literature," A Movable Feast, 1988-1989 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 11)
  - The Poetry Center, 1989 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 12)
  - "William Kennedy: The Singularity of Fiction," The Yale Vernacular, 1989-1990 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 13)
  - Contemporary Writers on Cassette New Letters on the Air, 1989; 1996 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 14)
  - "The Art of Fiction: William Kennedy," The Paris Review, Edited Pages and Correspondence, 1989; 1991; Undated (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 15)
  - Interview of Robert Penn Warren, 1991 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 16)
  - Writing! Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1 (18-Biographical), Folder 17)
  - "William Kennedy Interviewed by Tom Smith" The Public Radio Book Show, 1992 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 1)
  - "William Kennedy, Scruffy Soul and All", 1992-1993 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 2)
  - News Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 3)
  - Interview with William Kennedy, 1993 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 4)
  - Kennedy Profile in The San Juan Star, 1993 (Oversized 10, Folder 4)
  - William Kennedy's Albany, WETA, ca. 1994 (Video-tape 1)
  - Le Nouvel Observateur and A Day in Albany Profile, 1994-1995 (Oversized 10, Folder 5)
  - "A Conversation with William Kennedy," Image, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 6)
  - "Conversations with William Kennedy", 1995-1997 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 7-8)
  - "William Kennedy: Past, Passing, and to Come" The Boston Book Review, 1996 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 9)
  - Grand View Materials, 1996 (Oversized 10, Folder 6)
  - "Beyond Realism: William Kennedy on the Surreal and the Unconscious, the Religious, the Sublime and the Gonzo" New England Review, 1997 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 10)
  - "Conversations with William Kennedy," Manuscript, 1997 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 11-12)
  - Lennon Documentary Group, 1997 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 13)
  - Interview with Colonie High School Student, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 14)
  - "William Kennedy: Conversations with American Authors", 1997-1998 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 15)
  - "William Kennedy: A Reporter in An Imaginary World"Fiction Writer, 1998 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 16)
  - "Albany is My Kind of Town" Rough Draft Column, 1999 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 17)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, A&E Biography, 1999 (Box 2 (18-Biographical), Folder 18)
  - "Reading Matters," APME News, 1999 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 1)
  - "A Fertile Plain for a Writer," Hudson Valley Magazine, 2000 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 2)
  - "William Kennedy," Writer's Choice.net, 2000 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 3)
  - "It's Fiction Not Laurels, That Counts for Kennedy," Times-Union, 2001 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 4)
  - "Reverence for History: A Conversation with William Kennedy," New York State Archives, 2001 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 5)
  - "Prohibition in Upstate New York: Reaction and Reform," Averill Park High School History Club, 2002 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 6)
  - Celebration of the Acquisition of the Kennedy Papers, 2003 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 7)
  - "William Kennedy Discusses His Characters, His Influences, and His Albany," The Buffalo News, 2003 (Box 3 (18-Biographical), Folder 8)
  - Times-Union Article, Acquisition of the Kennedy Papers, 2003 (Oversized 10, Folder 7)
- Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland with President Clinton, 1990; 1993-1996; 1998; Undated; 19; .77 cu. ft.
  In 1995 William Kennedy accompanied President Bill Clinton to Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland as part of an American delegation, following a cease fire between the Irish Republican Army and the Loyalist Military Command in Northern Ireland in 1994. The delegation included elected officials, business, labor, religious, and community leaders and was designed to promote both peace and U.S. investment. This series documents that particular trip, including invitations, arrangements, news clips, maps, travel items, correspondence, and backgrounders. In addition, Kennedy and his wife attended a White House dinner in 1996 given by the Clintons in honor of the President of Ireland, Mary Robinson, and the first State visit by an Irish president in more than 30 years. The invitation and dinner menu and related correspondence also are included.
  - "An Irish Empire; The Time is Right", 1990 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 1)
  - News Clippings on Ireland, 1993-1995; Undated (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 2)
  - Photocopy of "Conference on Northern Ireland", 1994 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 3)
  - Statement of Gerry Adams, President of Sinn Fein, 1994 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 4)
  - Briefing on Northern Ireland Peace Process, 1994-1996 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 5)
  - Arrangements for Trip, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 6)
  - Brochures, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 7)
  - Fact Sheet on Ireland, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 8)
  - Information Brief on the Shannon Region of Ireland, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 9)
  - Invitations and Credentials from Trip to Ireland, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 11)
  - President Clinton's Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland, Speeches, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, Embassy of Ireland, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 13)
  - Springvale Training Facility, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 14)
  - "The Trip of President Clinton to Northern Ireland and Ireland" Briefing Book, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 15-16)
  - Irish America Magazine, 1995 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 17)
  - Shankill (Belfast) Newspapers and Business Backgrounder, 1995; Undated (Oversized 10, Folder 7)
  - Irish Newspaper Coverage of President Clinton's Trip, 1995 (Oversized 10, Folder 8-10)
  - Correspondence, 1995; 1998 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 18)
  - Irish State Dinner, White House Invitations, 1996 (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 19)
  - Map of Belfast, Undated (Box 1 (19-Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of ), Folder 20)